>> Jem Young: 我们正在为前端 V2 执行完整堆栈。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: We're doing Full Stack for
Front-End V2.
我从 V1开始就有几年了
It's been a couple of years since V1.
你可能在想，服务器上的变化是什么 ?
And you're probably wondering,
what has changed on the server?
没有多少，这就是服务器的伟大。
Not much,
that's what's great about the server.
服务器不会让你失望的
The server won't let you down.
服务器不更改。
The server doesn't change.
我有台服务器 10 年前还在运行
I have a server still
running from ten years ago.
我更新了但就是这样
I update it, but that's it.
我什么都没做
I don't do anything else to it.
我打赌我们不能对你的前端应用说同样的话
I bet we can't say the same
thing about your front-end app.
一点都不真实
Not true at all.
我也不喜欢前端，很明显，我也做前端的。
I'm not bashing front-end, obviously,
cuz I do front-end as well.
但我说的是满满的是它的位置
But I'm saying full stack,
it's where it's at.
我叫杰姆 - 扬
My name is Jem Young.
我是 Netflix公司的高级软件工程师。
I am a senior software
engineer at Netflix.
> > Jem Young: 我的妻子是创造性的。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: My wife is the creative one.
于是她编辑了这张照片
So she edited this photo.
那是我去年的万圣节服装我没穿
That was my Halloween costume for
last year that I didn't get to wear.
我希望我今年能穿上它
I'm hoping I get to wear it this year.
我们会看到的我们会看到的
We'll see, we'll see.
我还做的一件事就是我在播客 " 前端快乐小时"
One of the things I also do is I'm on
a podcast called Front End Happy Hour.
我们已经做了好几年了
We've been doing it several years now.
我这么做他是我的经纪人现在他只是 Netflix的另一个人
I do it with, he was my manager,
now he's just another guy at Netflix.
还是一个经理，我只是有个不同的经理。
Still a manager,
I just have a different manager.
我们喝了酒谈正事，主要是这个，
And we have drinks and we talk about
front end stuff, and mainly this,
但在较短的时间里还有更多的酒
but for shorter periods of time and
with more alcohol.
所以这很有趣
So it's pretty entertaining.
>> Jem Young: 如果你想看今天的幻灯片
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: If you wanna
see the slides today and
这种情况是在 jemyoung.com/fsfe上
kind of keep up,
it's at jemyoung.com/fsfe.
那是满满的堆栈前端
That's full stack front-end.
上次我把满满的都搞糊涂了，连我都混了
Last time I did front-end full stack and
it got really confusing, cuz even I mixed
你应该在正前方的地方
it up, but full stack front-end,
you should be at the right place.
如果幻灯片不是黑色的，您就会以某种方式处理旧的幻灯片。
If the slides are not black,
you're on the old slides somehow.
我不知道你是怎么做到的
I don't know how you got there.
今天我们要去几个地方
Today we're gonna cover a few parts.
第二天我们要用引号来掩饰
And day one we're gonna cover full sack,
in quotes.
我们将覆盖命令行，订购炮弹，因特网的运作方式，
We're gonna cover the command line,
order shells, how the Internet works,
我最喜欢的问题之一
one of my favorite questions.
然后我们就会覆盖 VIM
And then we're gonna cover VIM.
我们会不时地休息好吧
We're gonna take breaks from
time to time just because, well,
我们会学到很多新信息我们会加载这些信息的
we're gonna learn a lot of new information
and we're gonna load up on that.
我不想让任何人超负荷所以我们会不时地休息
And I don't wanna overload anybody, so
we'll take breaks from time to time.
如果我们走得太远或者你需要跟上，就说，嘿，
And if we're going too far or
you need to catch up, just say, hey,
杰姆我需要休息
Jem, I need a break.
我们要五个，没关系
And we'll take five, that's okay.
>> Jem Young: 什么是完整的堆栈?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: What is full stack?
任何人，任何人，房间里的任何人，你都能告诉我完整的堆栈是什么吗 ?
Anybody, anybody, anybody in the room,
you could just tell me what full stack is?
什么是全堆工程师
What's a full stack engineer?
>> Jem Young: 没有人。 有些
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: No one at all.
Some
你说你是个满满的工程师对吧
of you said you're a full stack engineers,
so, yes?
>> 扬声器 2: 那么，从客户机到
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Well, everything
from the client all the way up to
服务器 - >> Jem Young: 是。
the server-
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah.
>> 扬声器 2: 数据存储器。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: The data stores.
>> Jem Young: 是的， >> Jem Young: 我喜欢这样。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah,
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: I like that.
完全堆栈的事情是很有争议的。
The thing about full stack
is it's very contentious.
有些人不可能是一个完整的工程师。
There are people that are like it's
not possibly a full stack engineer.
这还不是真的
That's not even a real thing.
显然我不同意
Obviously I disagree.
大部分我不同意布莱恩 - 霍尔特是我的朋友和对手
And mostly I disagree with Bryan Holt,
who is my friend and rival,
苦涩的对手
bitter, bitter rival.
他说这是一个完整的开发者。
[LAUGH] He says this is
a full stack developer.
老实说我同意他的说法
And honestly, I agree with him.
我认为在这堆堆的每一部分都是不可能的。
I think it is almost impossible to
be good at every part of the stack.
你可以在前端做得好，你可以很擅长一些后端的工作。
You can be good at the front-end, you can
be good at probably some of the back-end.
您可能对数据库很有好处。
You might be good at databases.
你可能很安全
You might be good at security.
您可能很擅长调整性能。
You might be good at performance tuning.
你可能在 3D 动画里很棒但是真的
You might be amazing at 3D animations,
but it's really, really,
真的很难让他们大惊大惊艳
really, really,
really hard to be amazing at all of them.
世界上很少有人会这样做。
There's very few people
in the world that are.
所以如果有部分你不太明白你就会很酷
So if there's parts you don't quite
understand, you're like that's cool but
我不想太沉下去太好了
I don't really wanna dive into
it too much, that's okay.
那应该是这样
That's the way it should be.
找到你热爱的地方然后再去挖掘
Find the area that you're passionate
about and then kind of dig into that and
成为了这方面的专家
become an expert at that end.
>> Jem Young: 但是当我们说，什么是完整的堆，很多正面的工程师，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: But when we say, what is
full stack, a lot of frontend engineers,
尤其是在前面有个前端，有一个后端。
especially, they're like, well, there's
a frontend, there's a backend somewhere.
然后它一起工作我不知道
And then it works together somehow,
I don't know.
有人刚做了 API 我就给它打了电话
Someone just made an API and I call it.
我从未想过这么多工作的想法
I've never really given it a lot
of thought about how that works.
或者你做了很多的后端工作，你的意思是，我制作这些 API 和
Or maybe you do a lot of backend work, and
you're saying, well, I make these APIs and
然后它会以某种方式调用它，然后建立起来，然后它就会走到一起。
then the frontend calls it somehow and
it gets built, and it comes together.
我不知道它就在某种程度上
I don't know,
it just comes together somehow.
这就是我几年前的地方。
And this is where I was a few years ago.
我只是觉得
I just thought, well,
我不需要担心因为我永远不会碰它
I don't need to worry about that
because I'll never touch it.
这不是真的。
And that's not quite true.
在你的职业生涯的某个时刻，你必须在后端工作。
At some point in your career,
you're gonna have to work on the backend.
或者你得在码头工作
Or you're gonna have to
work in the terminal.
或者你得弄明白怎么去做什么
Or you're gonna have to work figure
out how to SSH into something and
查看数据库。
look at a database.
你得学着这些东西
You're gonna have to
learn all these things.
这就是这个课的内容。
And that's what this class is for.
>> Jem Young: 为何完整的栈如此定义 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And
why is full stack such a hard definition?
因为前端是很难定义的
Well, because frontend is
hard enough to define.
因此，前端可能是一辆汽车。
So frontend, it could be a car.
汽车有 UIs。
Cars have UIs.
其中一些是用 JavaScript 编写的。
Some of them are written in JavaScript.
它可以是电视
It can be a TV.
显然是浏览器
Browsers, obviously.
桌面应用，移动设备。
There's desktop apps, mobile devices.
像冰箱之类的电器之类的
There's appliances like refrigerators and
things like that.
我只是在把它作为一个前端的工程师的意思擦去。
And I'm just skimming the surface of
what it means to be a frontend engineer.
很多时候人们会说，嗯，正面是很难的，但是
And a lot of times people say,
yeah, frontend is hard, but
对前方的采访更加困难。
interviewing for frontend is even harder.
这是为什么呢 ?
And it is, and why?
因为这一切
Because of all this.
从字面上来说，前端覆盖了许多不同的用例，这将是
Literally, frontend covers so
many different use cases, which would be
总是很难精确地确定一个定义是什么
frontend, that it's really hard to nail
down exactly what a definition is.
别担心，后端也同样复杂。
And don't fret,
the backend is just as complicated too.
你说我在后端工作
You say, I work on the backend.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
您可以构建 API。
You could be building APIs.
你可能是数据科学家
You might be a data scientist.
你可以做保安
You might do security.
你可能会承担网络责任
You might do cyber liability.
您可能是某种数据库工程师，数据库管理员。
You might be some sort of database
engineer, database admin.
或者你只是在平台上工作
Or you might just work on the platform.
或者你可以做嵌入式软件。
Or you could do embedded software.
或者你可以做很多被认为是后端的事情。
Or you can do a lot of things
that are considered backend.
但它又不是很硬的定义
But again, it doesn't really
have a hard definition, but
我们喜欢说前端和后端，以帮助区分人员。
we like to say frontend and
backend just to help differentiate people.
所以，我们今天将会学到很多新的东西。
So, again, we're gonna learn
a lot of new things today.
如果你不跟你有什么关系，或者不坚持，别担心，
If something doesn't quite click with
you or doesn't stick, don't worry,
我们今天的事太多了
we're covering so much stuff today.
>> Jem Young: 那么，这一天到底是什么呢 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: So again,
what is full stack at the end of the day?
我喜欢你的定义
I liked your definition,
这是一个可以从一开始就可以构建应用程序的人。
which is someone who can build
an application from start to finish.
很简单直说吧
Pretty simple, pretty straightforward.
如果我说我想下一个 Netflix的话
It's someone that if I say I
wanna make the next Netflix,
我想下一个脸书那个人
I wanna make the next Facebook,
that person,
我可以给你，然后开始，你就结束了。
I can give it to you, and
then will start and you'll finish.
你会从这个疯狂的想法到终点线
You'll come from this crazy idea
to all the way to the finish line.
这意味着服务器，数据库。
That means the server, the database.
所有这些事情之间的安全
All these things between, security.
如果这听起来很令人畏惧，那是因为它是。
If that sounds daunting,
it's because it is.
真的，真的很难在这些事情上做得很好。
[LAUGH] It's really, really, really
difficult to be good at all these things.
但今天我们要学习如何才能真正了解
But today we're gonna learn all the skills
needed to just understand exactly what's
发生了什么
happening.